慢点  伙计
Easy, boy.
他们是野人  还能怎么样
What do you expect? They're savages.
这伙顺手牵了那伙的山羊
One lot steals a goat from another lot,
你还没反应过来  已经杀得碎尸满地了
before you know it they're ripping each other to pieces.
我没见过野人会做这种事
I've never seen wildlings do a thing like this.
活到现在都没见过这种场面
I never seen a thing like this, not ever in my life.
-你离得多远  -不能再近了
- How close did you get? - Close as any man would.
我们应该返回长城
We should head back to the wall.
死人吓着你了吗
Do the dead frighten you?
我们受命追查野人行踪
Our orders were to track the wildlings.
已完成任务  现在野人不会骚扰我们了
We tracked them. They won't trouble us no more.
你以为他不会追问野人的死因吗
You don't think he'll ask us how they died?
去牵马
Get back on your horse.
不管是什么杀了野人  也可能杀死我们
Whatever did it to them could do it to us.
那些家伙连孩童都没放过
They even killed the children.
值得庆幸  你我皆非孩童
It's a good thing we're not children.
你想往南逃  尽管去吧
You want to run away south, run away.
到时自然要被当作逃兵砍头
Of course they will behead you as a deserter,
还要看你能否先过我这一关
if I don't catch you first.
快去牵马
Get back on your horse.
我说最后一次
I won't say it again.
看来你说的那些死人转移阵地了呀
Your dead men seem to have moved camp.
刚才就在这里
They were here.
瞧瞧他们去哪儿了
See where they went.
那是什么
What is it?
是...
It's...
权力的游戏
第一季 第一集-凛冬将至
临冬城
□
继续  父亲正看着你
Go on, father's watching.
你母亲也在
And your mother.
一如既往的漂亮  非常好
Fine work as always. Well done.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
我真喜欢你绣在边角的花纹
I love the detail that you've managed to get in these corners.
太漂亮了
Quite beautiful.
针脚...
The stitching...
你们笑的几个  十岁就是神箭手了吗
And which one of you was a marksman at 10?
接着练  布兰
Keep practicing, Bran.
继续
Go on.
别想太多  布兰
Don't think too much, Bran.
持弓臂放松
Relax your bow arm.
布兰  跑快点
Quick, Bran! Faster.
史塔克大人
Lord Stark!
夫人
My lady.
有巡山的卫兵刚刚来报
A guardsman just rode in from the hills.
说他们捉获一个守夜人逃兵
They've captured a deserter from the Night's Watch.
让孩子们备马
Get the lads to saddle their horses.
非杀不可吗
Do you have to?
他背弃了誓言  凯特
He swore an oath, Cat.
法律就是法律  夫人
The law is law, my lady.
告诉布兰他也要去
Tell Bran he's coming too.
奈德
Ned.
他才十岁  观刑还太小
10 is too young to see such things.
他不会永远都是个孩子
He won't be a boy forever.
况且凛冬将至
And winter is coming.
好小子  快去把剩下的都找回来
Good lad, go run back and get the rest.
白鬼
White walkers.
我看到了白鬼
I saw the white walkers.
白鬼
White walkers.
白鬼  我都看见了
The white walkers, I saw them.
我违背了誓言
I know I broke my oath.
我知道我是逃兵
And I know I'm a deserter.
我应该回长城去警告他们  可...
I should have gone back to the wall and warned them, but...
我亲眼所见
I saw what I saw.
我看到了白鬼
I saw the white walkers.
要让大家知道
People need to know.
如果您能给我家人捎句话...
If you can get word to my family...
告诉他们我不是懦夫
Tell them I'm no coward.
告诉他们我很抱歉
Tell them I'm sorry.
原谅我  大人
Forgive me, lord.
以拜拉席恩家族的劳勃一世
In the name of Robert of the House Baratheon, the first of his name...
千万别扭头
Don't look away.
安达尔人  洛伊拿人和先民的国王
...King of the Andals and the First Men...
父亲会知道
Father will know if you do.
七国统治者暨全境守护者之名
...Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and protector of the realm,
我  史塔克家族的艾德
I, Eddard of the House Stark,
临冬城公爵  北境守护
Lord of Winterfell and warden of the north,
宣判你死刑
sentence you to die.
你做得很好
You did well.
你知道为什么我要杀他
You understand why I did it?
琼恩说他是逃兵
Jon said he was a deserter.
你可明白我为何要亲自行刑
But do you understand why I had to kill him?
我们遵循古老的传统
"Our way is the old way"?
判人死刑者必须亲自动手
The man who passes the sentence should swing the sword.
他真的看到白鬼了吗
Is it true he saw the white walkers?
白鬼数千年前已销声匿迹
The white walkers have been gone for thousands of years.
那他说的是谎话
So he was lying?
疯癫之人所见皆是疯癫
A madman sees what he sees.
什么野兽干的
What is it?
是山狮吗
Mountain lion?
附近森林里没有山狮
There are no mountain lions in these woods.
一头怪物
It's a freak!
是冰原狼
It's a direwolf.
顽强的野兽
Tough old beast.
绝境长城以南没有冰原狼
There are no direwolves south of the wall.
眼前不就有五头
Now there are five.
要抱抱它吗
You want to hold it?
小狼怎么办呢
Where will they go?
它们的妈妈死了
Their mother's dead.
它们不属于这里
They don't belong down here.
不如干脆趁早了结
Better a quick death.
没有母狼它们活不长
They won't last without their mother.
-这就对了  把它给我  -不
- Right. Give it here. - No!
把匕首收起来
Put away your blade.
我听令于你父亲  不是你
I take orders from your father, not you.
-求你了  父亲  -对不起  布兰
- Please, father! - I'm sorry, Bran.
史塔克大人
Lord Stark?
总共有五只小狼
There are five pups...
史塔克家族的孩子们每人一只
One for each of the Stark children.
冰原狼是您家族的纹章
The direwolf is the sigil of your house.
他们注定要拥有这些小狼
They were meant to have them.
你们得亲自训练它们
You will train them yourselves.
亲自喂养他们
You will feed them yourselves.
如果小狼夭折  你们也要亲手埋葬它们
And if they die, you will bury them yourselves.
你怎么办
What about you?
我并非史塔克家族的一员
I'm not a Stark.
走吧
Get on.
这是什么
What is it?
雪诺啊  此为窝中劣种  非你莫属
The runt of the litter... That one's yours, Snow.
君临
□
___
七国之都
身为弟弟  我觉得有义务提醒你
As your brother, I feel it's my duty to warn you:
你思虑太重  要添皱纹的
you worry too much. It's starting to show.
而你从不为任何事忧虑
And you never worry about anything.
我们七岁那年你就敢跳凯岩城的悬崖
When we were seven and you jumped off the cliffs at Casterly Rock,
崖顶离水面足足一百尺
100-foot drop into the water,
而你毫不畏惧
and you were never afraid.
如果你不告诉父亲  本来就没什么可怕的
There was nothing to be afraid of until you told father.
"我们是兰尼斯特
"We're Lannisters.
兰尼斯特家不可有愚行"
Lannisters don't act like fools."
如果琼恩·艾林已经告诉别人了呢
What if Jon Arryn told someone?
他能告诉谁
But who would he tell?
-我丈夫  -如果他告诉了国王
- My husband. - If he told the king, both our heads
你我的头颅现在已经挂在城门口了
would be skewered on the city gates by now.
不管琼恩·艾林知晓何事  都会带进坟墓了
Whatever Jon Arryn knew or didn't know, it died with him.
劳勃会选一位新首相
And Robert will choose a new Hand of the King...
代他处理政务
someone to do his job
好让他继续操野猪猎妓女
while he's off fucking boars and hunting whores...
我没说反吧
Or is it the other way around?
生活会继续
And life will go on.
当首相的应该是你才对
You should be the Hand of the King.
这份殊荣我可不敢享受
That's an honor I can do without.
他们度日如年
Their days are too long,
而又朝不保夕
their lives are too short.
这么多年了
All these years
每当来到这里
and I still feel like an outsider
我仍然觉得自己是个外人
when I come here.
你养育了五个北方的孩子
You have five northern children.
怎可能还算外人
You're not an outsider.
不知道旧神是不是同意你的话
I wonder if the old gods agree.
你的七神才喜欢立规矩
It's your gods with all the rules.
亲爱的  我非常遗憾
I am so sorry, my love.
-说吧  -君临有乌鸦带信来
- Tell me. - There was a raven from King's Landing.
琼恩·艾林过世了
Jon Arryn is dead.
热病夺走了他
A fever took him.
我知道他对你亲如父亲
I know he was like a father to you.
-你妹妹和那男孩呢  -他们安然无恙
- Your sister, the boy? - They both have their health,
诸神慈悲
gods be good.
信上还说
The raven brought more news...
国王正前来临冬城
The king rides for Winterfell...
带着王后
with the queen
和所有朝臣
and all the rest of them.
他千里迢迢北上
If he's coming this far north,
只可能有一个目的
there's only one thing he's after.
奈德  你可以拒绝的
You can always say no, Ned.
提利昂大人的房间要备好大量蜡烛
We'll need plenty of candles for Lord Tyrion's chamber.
据说他通宵读书
I'm told he reads all night.
我倒听说他通宵饮酒
I'm told he drinks all night.
他能喝多少酒啊  他那样的...
How much could he possibly drink? A man of his...
身量
stature?
我们从酒窖里取了八桶麦酒
We've brought up eight barrels of ale from the cellar.
-说不定到时候就知道了  -不管怎样
- Perhaps we'll find out. - In any case,
蜡烛不能少
candles.
你母亲为何硬要我们打扮漂亮见国王呢
Why is your mother so dead set on us getting pretty for the King?
肯定是为了见王后吧
It's for the Queen, I bet.
听说她是个挺讲究的女人
I hear she's a sleek bit of mink.
听说王子是正宗的王族傻屌
I hear the Prince is a right royal prick.
想想他用那根傻屌
Think of all those southern girls he gets to stab
日过多少南方姑娘
with his right royal prick.
继续  托米  好好给他剪
Go on, Tommy, shear him good.
还没有姑娘能撼动他对自己头发的喜爱
He's never met a girl he likes better than his own hair.
天哪  它们长得真快
Gods, but they grow fast.
布兰登
Brandon!
我看见国王了  他率领着上百号人马
I saw the king. He's got hundreds of people.
我跟你说过多少次不要爬墙了
How many times have I told you no climbing?
但是他马上就要到了  就在大道上
But he's coming right now... down our road.
我要你向我保证
I want you to promise me,
不再爬墙了
no more climbing.
我保证
I promise.
-你知道吗  -什么
- Do you know what? - What?
你在撒谎之前总会低头看脚
You always look at your feet before you lie.
跑去告诉你父亲  说国王马上就到
Run and find your father. Tell him the King is close.
艾莉亚哪儿去了  珊莎  你妹妹呢
Where's Arya? Sansa, where's your sister?
你戴着这玩意儿干什么
What are you doing with that on?
过去
Go on.
闪开
Move!
陛下
Your Grace.
你发福了
You've got fat.
-凯特  -陛下
- Cat! - Your Grace.
九年了  怎么就见不到你呢
Nine years... Why haven't I seen you?
你都到哪里去了
Where the hell have you been?
为您守护北境  陛下
Guarding the north for you, Your Grace.
临冬城听候您差遣
Winterfell is yours.
-小恶魔呢  -能不能闭嘴
- Where's the Imp? - Will you shut up?
瞧瞧这里都有谁
Who have we here?
你一定是罗柏了
You must be Robb.
真是个美人胚子
My, you're a pretty one.
你叫什么名字
Your name is?
艾莉亚
Arya.
给我们展示一下你的肌肉
Oh, show us your muscles.
未来定是勇士
You'll be a soldier.
那是詹姆·兰尼斯特  王后的双胞胎弟弟
That's Jaime Lannister, the Queen's twin brother.
你能闭嘴吗
Would you please shut up?
王后陛下
My Queen.
带我到你们家墓窖去  我要聊表敬意
Take me to your crypt. I want to pay my respects.
我们赶了一个月的路  亲爱的
We've been riding for a month, my love.
要看死人也不用这么着急
Surely the dead can wait.
奈德
Ned.
小恶魔在哪儿
Where's the Imp?
我们的弟弟哪儿去了
Where is our brother?
去找找那个小畜生
Go and find the little beast.
跟我说说琼恩·艾林的事
Tell me about Jon Arryn.
前一分钟还好好的  然后就...
One minute he was fine and then...
病魔犹如烈火  活活把他给燃尽了
Burned right through him, whatever it was.
我敬爱那个人
I loved that man.
我们都一样
We both did.
你倒是让他省心  可我就不同了
He never had to teach you much, but me?
还记得我十六岁那会儿吗
You remember me at 16?
我脑子里只有
All I wanted to do
打打杀杀和骄奢淫逸的念头
was crack skulls and fuck girls.
-他教会了我是是非非  -是啊
- He showed me what was what. - Aye.
别这样看我  我没听话不是他的错
Don't look at me like that. It's not his fault I didn't listen.
我需要你  奈德
I need you, Ned...
来君临助我
down at King's Landing,
你躲在这鬼地方  毫无用武之地
not up here where you're no damn use to anybody.
艾德·史塔克大人
Lord Eddard Stark,
我将任命你为国王之手  御前首相
I would name you the Hand of the King.
恐怕我不足以胜任此等要职
I'm not worthy of the honor.
我可不是为你着想
I'm not trying to honor you.
我是打算让你来治理国家
I'm trying to get you to run my kingdom
而我自己痛痛快快地吃喝玩乐  嫖个过瘾
while I eat, drink and whore my way to an early grave.
妈的  奈德  起来
Damn it, Ned, stand up.
你既然帮我得到了这张该死的铁椅子
You helped me win the Iron Throne,
就该帮我保住它吧
now help me keep the damn thing.
我们注定是要并肩治理国家的
We were meant to rule together.
倘若你妹妹还活着  我们现在就是联姻手足
If your sister had lived, we'd have been bound by blood.
好在现在也不迟
Well, it's not too late.
我有个儿子  你有个女儿
I have a son, you have a daughter.
我们两家会结合在一起
We'll join our houses.
北境的女孩果然与传言的一样
It is true what they say about the northern girls.
你听说国王来临冬城了吗
Did you hear the King's in Winterfell?
我确实有所耳闻
I did hear something about that.
还有王后和她的双胞胎弟弟
And the Queen and her twin brother.
据说他是七国之内最英俊的男子
They say that he is the most handsome man in the Seven Kingdoms.
那另一个弟弟呢
And the other brother?
-王后有两个弟弟吗  -一个英俊潇洒
- The queen has two brothers? - There's the pretty one,
一个聪明绝顶
and there's the clever one.
听说他人称小恶魔
Mmm, I hear they call him the Imp.
我听说他讨厌这个绰号
I hear he hates that nickname.
是吗  听说他实至名归啊
Oh? I hear he's more than earned it.
还听说他是个嗜酒的小色鬼
I hear he's a drunken little lecher,
喜欢玩各种各样的体位
prone to all manner of perversions.
真聪明
Clever girl.
我们非常期待您的到来  提利昂大人
We've been expecting you, Lord Tyrion.
真的吗
Have you?
又有反应了
Oh! Already?
诸神总算赐我一项天赋
The gods gave me one blessing.
-不用起身了  -见过大人
- Don't get up. - My lord.
需要我向你解释下妓院紧闭房门
Should I explain to you the meaning of a closed door
意味着什么吗  哥哥
in a whorehouse, brother?
毫无疑问  我还有很多需要向你学习
You have much to teach me, no doubt,
但我们的姐姐急需你的关心
but our sister craves your attention.
我们的这位姐姐需求很奇特
She has odd cravings, our sister.
家族特性
A family trait.
史塔克家要在日落时分为我们设宴接风
Now the Starks are feasting us at sundown.
别让我独自面对那些家伙
Don't leave me alone with these people.
抱歉  我的宴席提前了一些
I'm sorry, I've begun the feast a bit early.
而这是开胃菜
And this is the first of many courses.
就知道你会这么说
I thought you might say that.
既然时间仓促
But since we're short on time...
进来吧  姑娘们
Come on, girls.
日落时见
See you at sundown.
关门
Close the door!
有必要把她葬在这种地方吗
Did you have to bury her in a place like this?
她应该安息在山丘上
She should be on a hill somewhere
有阳光白云作伴
with the sun and the clouds above her.
她是我妹妹
She was my sister.
这里是她的归宿
This is where she belongs.
曾经  我才是她的归宿
She belonged with me.
每晚在梦中  我都要杀他一次
In my dreams, I kill him every night.
您已经杀了他  陛下
It's done, Your Grace.
坦格利安家族灭亡了
The Targaryens are gone.
还未斩草除根
Not all of them.
潘托斯
□
___
狭海彼岸
丹妮莉丝
Daenerys!
Daenerys.
原来准新娘在这里
There's our bride-to-be.
看哪  伊利里欧送你的礼物
Look, a gift from Illyrio.
摸摸看
Touch it.
来呀  瞧瞧这料子
Go on, feel the fabric.
他真是个体贴的主人
Isn't he a gracious host?
我们在这儿作客一年多了
We've been his guests for over a year
他从未有求于我们
and he's never asked us for anything.
伊利里欧可不笨
Illyrio's no fool.
他知道有朝一日当我重登王位
He knows I won't forget my friends
不会忘记曾经雪中送炭的朋友
when I come into my throne.
你总是弯腰驼背
You still slouch.
让他们见识一下
Let them see.
你已有成熟女人的曼妙身姿了
You have a woman's body now.
今天不许出差错
I need you to be perfect today.
为了我  能做到吗
Can you do that for me?
你不想唤醒睡龙之怒吧
You don't want to wake the dragon, do you?
不想
No.
将来史家为我立传时  亲爱的妹妹
When they write the history of my reign, sweet sister,
会说我的统治始自今日
they will say it began today.
水还很烫  公主殿下
It's too hot, my lady.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
多斯拉克人并非以守时闻名
The Dothraki are not known for their punctuality.
[多斯拉克语]
Athchomar chomakaan, Khal vezhven.
容许我介绍两位尊贵的客人
May I present my honored guests?
来自坦格利安家族的
Viserys of House Targaryen,
韦赛里斯三世
the third of his name,
统领安达尔人和先民的真王
the rightful King of the Andals and the First Men,
以及他的妹妹
and his sister
坦格利安家族的丹妮莉丝
Daenerys of House Targaryen.
你看到他的头发有多长了没
Do you see how long his hair is?
每当多斯拉克人在战斗中落败
When Dothraki are defeated in combat,
他们便割去辫子以示不誉
they cut off their braids so the whole world can see their shame.
卓戈卡奥一辈子没吃过败仗
Khal Drogo has never been defeated.
当然了  他是野蛮人
He's a savage, of course,
但堪称世上最优秀的杀手
but one of the finest killers alive.
而你将成为他的王后
And you will be his queen.
来这边  我的公主
Come forward, my dear.
他要去哪儿
Where is he going?!
-仪式结束了  -但他还什么都没说
- The ceremony is over. - But he didn't say anything.
-他看上她了吗  -相信我  陛下
- Did he like her? - Trust me, Your Grace,
如果不喜欢她  他会让我们知道的
if he didn't like her, we'd know.
不会等太久了
It won't be long now.
很快您就会渡过狭海
Soon you will cross the Narrow Sea
重夺您父亲的王座
and take back your father's throne.
人们偷偷举杯
The people drink secret toasts
祝您龙体安康
to your health.
他们渴望真王归来
They cry out for their true king.
他们什么时候成婚
When will they be married?
很快  多斯拉克人从不在一个地方久留
Soon. The Dothraki never stay still for long.
他们真的连马都搞吗
Is it true they lie with their horses?
我可不会当面问卓戈卡奥
I wouldn't ask Khal Drogo.
你当我是笨蛋
Do you take me for a fool?
我当您是个王者
I take you for a king.
所谓王者无凡虑
Kings lack the caution of common men.
倘若我冒犯了您  那么我向您道歉
My apologies if I've given offense.
我知道怎么和卓戈这种人打交道
I know how to play a man like Drogo.
我许给他一个王后  他就要送我一支军队
I give him a queen and he gives me an army.
我不要做他的王后
I don't want to be his queen.
我想回家
I want to go home.
我也是
So do I.
我想和你一起回家
I want us both to go home,
可我们的家早给人夺走了
but they took it from us.
好妹妹  你倒是说说看
So tell me, sweet sister,
我们怎么回家啊
how do we go home?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们带着军队回去
We go home with an army.
带着卓戈卡奥的千军万马回家
With Khal Drogo's army.
就算让他部落的四万人通通把你操上一遍
I would let his whole tribe fuck you...
我也会同意  必要的话
All 40,000 men and their horses too
连他们的马一起上也行
if that's what it took.
你觉得乔佛里王子会喜欢我吗
Do you think Joffrey will like me?
要是他觉得我不好看呢
What if he thinks I'm ugly?
那他就是世界上最蠢的王子
Then he is the stupidest prince that ever lived.
他是那么的英俊潇洒
He's so handsome.
我们何时结婚  很快吗  还是要等一阵子
When would we be married? Soon? Or do we have to wait?
先别提这个  你父亲还没同意呢
Hush now. Your father hasn't even said yes.
他怎么会拒绝
Why would he say no?
他将成为王国里一人之下  万人之上的男人
He'd be the second most powerful man in the kingdoms.
那样他就不得不离开家乡
He'd have to leave home.
不得不离开我
He'd have to leave me.
你也是
And so would you.
你当初就是离开家乡来到这里
You left your home to come here.
而我有朝一日会当王后
And I'd be queen someday.
拜托让父亲同意吧
Please make father say yes!
-珊莎  -求你了  求你了
- Sansa... - Please please!
这是我这辈子唯一的心愿
It's the only thing I ever wanted.
满上  小伙子们  罗德利克  来来来
Fill that up! Boys, Rodrik, come on.
干了
Come on!
还没砍死吗
Is he dead yet?
班扬叔叔
Uncle Benjen.
你长大了
You got bigger.
赶了一天路  不想让你独自面对兰尼斯特家
Rode all day. Didn't want to leave you alone with the Lannisters.
你怎么不去参加宴席
Why aren't you at the feast?
史塔克夫人认为  今晚若让私生子同桌用餐
Lady Stark thought it might insult the royal family
对王族是一种侮辱
to seat a bastard in their midst.
长城倒是永远欢迎你
Well, you're always welcome on the wall.
私生子在那儿都有座
No bastard was ever refused a seat there.
那回去的时候带我一道走吧
So take me with you when you go back.
-琼恩  -只要你跟父亲说  他一定会同意
- Jon... - Father will let me if you ask him.
我能肯定
I know he will.
长城又不会长腿跑掉
The wall isn't going anywhere.
我已经做好
I'm ready
宣誓加入的准备了
to swear your oath.
你无法想象要付出多大的代价
You don't understand what you'd be giving up.
我们不能成家
We have no families.
-永远不会生儿育女  -我才不在乎那个
- None of us will ever father sons... - I don't care about that!
你若能体会到其中滋味  就会在乎了
You might, if you knew what it meant.
我该进去了
I'd better get inside,
要帮你父亲应付宾客
rescue your father from his guests.
我们迟些再聊
We'll talk later.
你叔叔原来是个守夜人
Your uncle's in the Night's Watch.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing back there?
准备与你的家人彻夜狂欢
Preparing for a night with your family.
我早就想一睹长城的风采了
I've always wanted to see the wall.
你是那个提利昂·兰尼斯特
You're Tyrion Lannister,
王后的弟弟
the queen's brother?
算是我的最高成就吧
My greatest accomplishment.
而你是奈德·史塔克的私生子吧
And you... you're Ned Stark's bastard, aren't you?
我冒犯到你了吗  抱歉
Did I offend you? Sorry.
不过你确实是个私生子
You are the bastard though.
艾德·史塔克大人是我父亲没错
Lord Eddard Stark is my father.
而史塔克夫人不是你母亲
And Lady Stark is not your mother,
所以你是私生子
making you the bastard.
那么私生子小弟  让我给你一点建议吧
Let me give you some advice, bastard.
永远不要忘记自己的身份
Never forget what you are.
因为这个世界不会忘记
The rest of the world will not.
用它来武装自己
Wear it like armor
就没有人可以用它来伤害你
and it can never be used to hurt you.
身为私生子的感觉  你又知道什么
What the hell do you know about being a bastard?
全天下的侏儒在他们父亲眼里都是私生子
All dwarves are bastards in their father's eyes.
你在宴会上就像一头困在陷阱里的熊
You at a feast... It's like a bear in a trap.
我处决的那个男孩  你认识他吗
The boy I beheaded... Did you know him?
当然认识
Of course I did.
一个小年轻
Just a lad.
但绝非孬种  奈德
And he was tough, Ned,
是条真汉子
a true ranger.
可你看他都胡说些什么
He was talking madness.
居然说同行的兄弟死于白鬼之手
Said the walkers slaughtered his friends.
那两个守夜人确实失踪未归
The two he was with are still missing.
中了野人的埋伏罢了
Hmph. A wildling ambush.
可能吧
Maybe.
冰原狼在长城以南出现
Direwolves south of the wall,
异鬼现身的谣言
talk of the walkers,
还有我哥哥即将成为新的御前首相
and my brother might be the next Hand of the King.
看来真是凛冬将至啊
Winter is coming.
是啊  凛冬将至
-班扬叔叔  -罗伯侄子
- Uncle Benjen. - Robb boy.
-一切都好吗  -当然了
- How are you? - I'm good.
这是您第一次来北方吗  陛下
Is this your first time in the north, Your Grace?
是的  景色很美
Yes. Lovely country.
相比君临  这里可说极为严酷
I'm sure it's very grim after King's Landing.
我到现在还记得奈德第一次
I remember how scared I was when Ned brought me
带我来时  我有多害怕
up here for the first time.
你好啊  小美人
Hello, little dove.
你可真漂亮
But you are a beauty.
-你多大了  -十三岁  陛下
- How old are you? - 13, Your Grace.
长得挺高啊  还在长个吗
You're tall. Still growing?
我想是吧  陛下
I think so, Your Grace.
你有月事了吗
And have you bled yet?
还没有  陛下
No, Your Grace.
你的衣服是自己做的吗
Your dress, did you make it?
真是心灵手巧  日后定要为我做一些
Such a talent. You must make something for me.
听说以后我们可能是一家人呢
I hear we might share a grandchild someday.
我也听说了
I hear the same.
你的女儿在宫里定能出类拔萃
Your daughter will do well in the Capital.
这样的小美人可不能在此埋没一生
Such a beauty shouldn't stay hidden up here forever.
-借过  -我听说我们要做邻居了
- Your pardon. - I hear we might be neighbors soon.
-希望这不是谣传  -是真的
- I hope it's true. - Yes,
国王有意授予我首相之职
the king has honored me with his offer.
为了庆祝您新官上任
I'm sure we'll have a tournament
我们定会举办比武大赛  如果您没意见的话
to celebrate your new title... if you accept.
届时若能与您切磋  那就再好不过了
It would be good to have you on the field.
如今的比武越来越没意思了
The competition has become a bit stale.
-我不参加比武  -为什么
- I don't fight in tournaments. - No?
是感到力不从心吗
Getting a little old for it?
我不会参加比武
I don't fight in tournaments
是因为跟人真刀真枪地对决时
because when I fight a man for real
我不希望对方知道我的本事
I don't want him to know what I can do.
说得太好了
Well said.
艾莉亚
Arya!
你太过分了
It's not funny!
她总是捣乱
She always does this.
这是我最喜欢的衣服
This was my favorite dress.
她总是捣乱  这太过分了
She always does it and it's not funny!
该睡觉了
Time for bed.
我是北方人
I'm a Northman.
理应与你厮守于此  而不是南方那个
I belong here with you, not down south
名叫君临的鬼地方
in that rats' nest they call a Capital.
我不会让他带你走的
I won't let him take you.
国王想要  谁能说不
The king takes what he wants.
否则就不叫国王了
That's why he's king.
我会说  "听好了  胖子
I'll say, "Listen, fat man."
你不能带走我的丈夫
"You are not taking my husband anywhere.
他现在是属于我的"
He belongs to me now."
他怎么变得那么胖了
How did he get so fat?
除了吃和喝  他还干过别的事吗
He only stops eating when it's time for a drink.
鲁温学士求见  老爷
It's Maester Luwin, my lord.
让他进来
Send him in.
打扰了  老爷  夫人
Pardon, my lord, my lady.
有信使连夜赶到
A rider in the night...
送来你妹妹的信
From your sister.
-别走  -是从鹰巢城寄来的
- Stay. - This was sent from the Eyrie.
她回鹰巢城干什么
What's she doing at the Eyrie?
婚礼之后她就再没回过那里
She hasn't been back there since her wedding.
她说了什么
What news?
她是从君临逃走的
She's fled the Capital.
还说琼恩·艾林死于谋杀
She says Jon Arryn was murdered.
凶手是兰尼斯特家
By the Lannisters.
她说国王现在也不安全
She says the king is in danger.
她刚刚失去丈夫  凯特
She's fresh widowed, Cat.
根本不知道自己在说些什么
She doesn't know what she's saying.
如果这封信落到他人手里
Lysa's head would be on a spike right now
莱莎必死无疑
if the wrong people had found that letter.
要是她没有十足的把握
Do you think she would risk her life...
怎会拿自己的命
her son's life...
拿孩子的命冒这么大风险
if she wasn't certain her husband was murdered?
此事若属实
If this news is true
兰尼斯特家族觊觎王位
and the Lannisters conspire against the Throne,
除您之外  谁能勤王
who but you can protect the king?
他们刚刚杀了前任首相
They murdered the last hand.
你就想让奈德接任
Now you want Ned to take the job?
国王千里迢迢而来
The king rode for a month
就是来向大人求援的
to ask for Lord Stark's help.
大人是他唯一信任的人
He's the only one he trusts.
大人  您曾宣誓要效忠我王
You swore the king an oath, my lord.
他舍生忘死为劳勃打下江山
He's spent half his life fighting Robert's wars.
问心无愧  何来亏欠
He owes him nothing.
你父亲和兄长曾奉命南下
Your father and brother rode south once
结果一去不返
on a king's demand.
时局不同
A different time.
国王也不一样
A different king.
我何时能与卡奥面谈
When do I meet with the Khal?
我们得商讨出战事宜
We need to begin planning the invasion.
卓戈卡奥既已许你王冠
If Khal Drogo has promised you a crown,
-便不会食言  -那要何时给我
- you shall have it. - When?
待到他们的预兆显示宜战
When their omens favor war.
去他妈的多斯拉克预兆
I piss on Dothraki omens.
我为夺回王位已苦苦等了十七年
I've waited 17 years to get my throne back.
在多斯拉克婚礼上
A Dothraki wedding
若没有闹出至少三条人命  就算是失败
without at least three deaths is considered a dull affair.
[多斯拉克语]
Jadi, zhey Jorah Andahli!
Khal vezhven.
薄礼一份  献与新卡丽熙
A small gift, for the new khaleesi...
这是七国历史和歌谣传奇
Songs and Histories from the Seven Kingdoms.
多谢这位爵士
Thank you, ser.
你可是我故国臣民
Are you from my country?
在下熊岛的乔拉·莫尔蒙爵士
Ser Jorah Mormont of Bear Island.
曾服侍先王多年
I served your father for many years.
上天保佑  我愿永远服侍真龙天子
Gods be good, I hope to always serve the rightful king.
丹妮莉丝  这是龙蛋
Dragon's eggs, Daenerys,
来自亚夏以东的阴影之地
from the Shadow Lands beyond Asshai.
历经千万年而成化石
The ages have turned them to stone,
却依旧亮丽动人
but they will always be beautiful.
多谢总督
Thank you, magister.
她好漂亮
She's beautiful.
乔拉爵士  我不知道怎样
Ser Jorah, I don't know how to say
用多斯拉克语说谢谢
thank you in Dothraki.
多斯拉克语里没有谢谢
There is no word for thank you in Dothraki.
好好取悦他
Make him happy.
不
No.
你会通用语吗
Do you know the common tongue?
不
No.
你只知道这个字吗
Is "No" The only word that you know?
不
No.
昨晚够呛吧
Rough night, Imp?
如果我这样一场接一场地干
If I get through this without squirting
不累到虚脱才怪
from one end or the other, it'll be a miracle.
我可没选你去当猎手
I didn't pick you for a hunter.
我可是天下无敌  枪无虚发的
The greatest in the land... my spear never misses.
需要掏银子就不是打猎了
It's not hunting if you pay for it.
你的枪术还有当年精准吗
Are you as good with a spear as you used to be?
不比当年了  但较你还是略胜一筹
No, but I'm still better than you.
我也知道这样让你为难
I know what I'm putting you through.
但总归多谢你能应允下来
Thank you for saying yes.
不是逼不得已  我不会请你出山
I only ask you because I need you.
你是我的忠诚老友
You're a loyal friend.
听见没  忠诚老友
You hear me? A loyal friend.
除你之外别无他人
The last one I've got.
-我希望能堪此大任  -一定会的
- I hope I'll serve you well. - You will.
而且保证让你一改这副冷冰冰的德性
And I'll make sure you don't look so fucking grim all the time.
走吧  小伙子们  去猎几头野猪回来
Come on, boys, let's go kill some boar!
走吧
Come on, you.
停
Stop!
Stop.
你是不是疯了
Are you completely mad?
-他瞧见我们了  -放心  没事
- He saw us. - It's all right, it's all right.
-没事  -他瞧见我们了
- It's all right. - He saw us!
我听见了
I heard you the first time.
你这小家伙还真能爬啊
Quite the little climber, aren't you?
-小鬼  你几岁啦  -十岁
- How old are you, boy? - 10.
十岁
10.
瞧我为爱情做了什么
The things I do for love.